- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain.
全部：
是的，是的，船长。
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain.
全部：
是的，是的，船长。
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants.
全部：
海绵宝宝。
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants.
全部：
海绵宝宝。
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants.
全部：
海绵宝宝。
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants.
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝。
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants.
全部：
海绵宝宝。
SpongeBob SquarePants.
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants.
方裤。
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
- [crowing]
- [鸡鸣]
- [yawns]
- [哈欠]
[grunting]
Oh, yeah.
[咕噜声]
哦，是的。
There we go.
我们开始吧。
- Hee-hee-hee-hee-hee-hee.
- 嘻嘻嘻嘻嘻嘻嘻。
Fluoride to Desktop,
氟化物到桌面，
I'm in a position to raise no
suspicion, over.
我可以提出反对意见
怀疑，结束。
- Cut the poetry, Wordsworth.
- 剪掉诗歌，华兹华斯。
Did you
get Krab's hair sample yet?
你有吗
拿到蟹老板的头发样本了吗？
- Keep your pants on, woman.
- 穿上你的裤子，女人。
I'm gonna steal his hairs
right out of his razor.
我要偷他的头发
就从他的剃须刀里出来。
- I'll just grab the
razor here...
- 我会抓住
剃须刀这里...
- Wait. No. Auugh.
- 等待。不，哦。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[coughing]
[咳嗽]
Ehhh!
呃！
- [whistling]
- [gargling]
- [吹口哨]
- [漱口]
- Now for the rest of it.
- 现在剩下的部分。
- Augh!
- 啊啊！
[groaning]
[呻吟]
- Well, if it isn't my thieving
husband.
- 好吧，如果这不是我偷的
丈夫。
So did you bring me the...
那你给我带来了...
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- Hair?
- 头发？
I only needed one.
我只需要一个。
- Hee-hee-hee.
- 嘻嘻嘻。
You married a genius,
Karen.
你嫁给了一个天才，
凯伦。
Using the DNA from Krabs'
hair
使用螃蟹的 DNA
头发
and my own DNA from my
antennae...
以及我自己的 DNA
天线...
Ouch!
哎哟!
I will create a combo-clone
of me and Krabs
我将创建一个组合克隆
我和蟹蟹
to finally steal the
secret formula.
终于偷到了
秘密配方。
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha.
哈哈哈哈哈哈哈。
Behold Plankrab.
看普兰克拉布。
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Heh-heh-heh.
呵呵。
Arr-arr-arr-arr-arr.
啊啊啊啊啊啊啊啊。
- How is this a good thing?
- 这怎么是一件好事呢？
- Wake up, Karen.
- 醒醒吧，凯伦。
The Plankton side will know
everything
浮游生物那边会知道
一切
the Krab side knows.
蟹方知道。
It'll be easier than taking
candy from a baby.
这会比采取更容易
来自婴儿的糖果。
- Mm, and we know how
successful that was.
- 嗯，我们知道怎么做
那是成功的。
- [gobbling]
- [狼吞虎咽]
- This is different,
- 这是不同的，
isn't it,
Plankrab, my pretty?
不是吗，
Plankrab，我的美丽？
Now, here's my plan.
现在，这是我的计划。
- Don't waste your breath,
Plankteron.
- 别浪费口气了
浮游生物。
I already mapped out the
perfect plot
我已经规划好了
完美的情节
to swipe that formuler-ererer.
刷那个配方错误者。
- Great!
See you soon, P.K.
- 伟大的！
很快再见，P.K.
[sighs]
I love that guy.
[叹气]
我爱那个人。
Well, half of him anyway.
好吧，无论如何，他的一半。
Heh-heh-heh-heh-heh-heh.
哈哈哈哈哈哈哈。
[coughing]
[咳嗽]
Still got a hair in there.
里面还有一根头发。
[scatting]
[分散]
Where is Plankrab
with the secret formula?
Plankrab 在哪里
用秘密公式？
It's been over three minutes
already.
已经三分多钟了
已经。
Augh!
啊啊！
- Hmm, ooh.
[grunts]
- 嗯，哦。
[咕哝]
- All right, Twoface,
what's the big idea?
- 好吧，双脸，
有什么大主意吗？
What have you been doing
all this time?
你最近在做什么
一直这样？
- Oh, nothing much-erer.
- 哦，没什么特别的。
Just stealin' the
formuler-erer...
只是偷了
配方师-错误...
- Uh-whaaa?
- 呃-哇？
- Taking over the
restaurant-erer...
- 接管
餐厅-呃……
both: Hooray for Plankrab.
两人：普兰克拉布万岁。
He's the best boss ever.
他是有史以来最好的老板。
- And kicking Krabs out
on his booty-erererer.
- 把蟹蟹赶出去
在他的战利品犯人身上。
- [sobbing]
- [抽泣]
- B-b-but how?
- 但、但怎么办？
- All it took me, Hardy,
was a hearty handshake,
- 我付出了一切，哈代，
是一次热烈的握手，
the world's most persuasive
handshake that is.
世界上最有说服力的
握手就是这样。
It's me latest creation.
这是我最新的创作。
Put her there-erer,
matey.
把她放在那里——呃，
马蒂。
- An evil handshake.
- 邪恶的握手。
That's hands down the
dumbest thing I ever--huh?
这是毫无疑问的
我做过的最愚蠢的事——嗯？
Oh. Ohh. Heh-heh, yeah.
哦。哦。呵呵，是啊。
Oh, ohh, ahh, ahh.
哦哦哦啊啊啊啊
Yeah, yeah. Ahh!
是啊是啊。啊！
Yeah. Ohh-ho.
是的。噢-嗬。
Oh, your handshake is
exquisite.
哦，你的握手是
精致的。
I'd believe anything you say.
你说什么我都会相信。
- Then believe this,
Swabby.
- 那么请相信这一点，
拭子。
I'll also be commandeer-ering
the Chum Bucket from now on.
我也来霸占
从现在开始，密友桶。
- Ahh-ahh.
- 啊啊啊。
Sounds great to me, P.K.
对我来说听起来很棒，P.K.
- And I'm afraid your
services
- 我担心你的
服务
are no longer
required-ererered.
不再是
要求-错误。
- Gosh, I still can't
get over this handshake.
- 天哪，我还是不行
克服这次握手。
Ahh!
啊！
Augh!
啊啊！
I'm over it now.
我现在已经结束了。
- Ahh! Plankton.
- 啊！浮游生物。
Some creepy, one-eyed
crab took me restaurant.
有些令人毛骨悚然，独眼
螃蟹带我去餐厅。
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
- Wait a minute.
- 等一下。
I think he took mine too.
我想他也拿走了我的。
[both sobbing]
[两人都抽泣]
- I-I-I don't know what
happened.
- 我-我-我不知道什么
发生了。
But that was some handshake
of his, huh?
但那是一些握手
他的，嗯？
I mean...hoo-hoo!
我的意思是……呼呼！
- Snap out of the handshake.
- 停止握手。
It's a trick, Krabs.
这是一个诡计，蟹蟹。
A dirty, beautiful trick.
一个肮脏而美丽的把戏。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
♪ ♪
- Ahh!
- 啊！
- [grunting]
- Ugh!
- [咕哝]
- 呃！
- Say, his Krabby Patty tastes
even better than usual.
- 比如说，他的蟹黄饼口味
甚至比平时更好。
What's in it,
SpongeBob?
里面有什么，
海绵宝宝？
- Well, it's the same old
patty,
- 嗯，还是老样子
帕蒂,
except now each one has a pinch
of chum added.
只是现在每个人都有一点点
密友补充道。
- A pinch of ch-ch-ch-chum?
- 一点ch-ch-ch-chum？
- Good work, me boy-o.
- 干得好，我的孩子。
- Wow.
- 哇。
- Me boy-o?
- 我男孩-o？
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
- [sighs] There's only one way
to get
- [叹气]只有一种方法
得到
our restaurants back,
Eugene.
我们的餐厅回来了，
尤金.
- Ahh!
You don't mean...
- 啊！
你不是说...
both: We gotta work together.
双方：我们必须共同努力。
- [coughing]
- [咳嗽]
Hair.
头发。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- ♪ Doo-doo-doo ♪
- ♪ 嘟嘟嘟 ♪
Mm-hmm. Mm-mm-mm.
嗯嗯。嗯嗯嗯。
Heh-heh-heh.
呵呵。
♪ Doo-doo-doo ♪
♪ 嘟嘟嘟 ♪
[whistling]
[吹口哨]
[both chuckling]
[两人都笑了]
- Hey, what the...
- 嘿，这是什么……
[all grunting]
[全都咕哝]
- Hee-hee, hee-hee-hee,
hee-hee.
- 嘻嘻，嘻嘻嘻，
嘻嘻。
- Ugh!
- 呃！
- Heh-heh-heh-heh-heh.
- 嘿嘿嘿嘿嘿嘿。
both: Ohh!
两人：哦！
- [whistling]
- [吹口哨]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
He may have taken our
restaurants,
他可能夺走了我们的
餐馆,
but we'll take his customers.
但我们会带走他的顾客。
[both chuckling]
[两人都笑了]
[bell dings]
[铃声]
[laughter]
[笑声]
- This way.
- 这边走。
[horn honks]
[喇叭鸣响]
Drive-thru. Literally.
得来速。字面上地。
both: Waahhh!
两人：哇啊啊！
- [whistling]
- [吹口哨]
- All right, all right.
- 好吧，好吧。
I can't go any lower, Eugene.
我不能再低了，尤金。
Please make it stop.
请让它停止。
- Ehhh...ugh!
- 呃……呃！
- It looks like there's
only one way
- 好像有
只有一种方式
out of this one, Sheldon.
从这个中，谢尔顿。
- Oh, no. You don't mean...
- 哦，不。你不是说...
- Yeah. I'm afraid so.
- 是的。恐怕是这样。
- [whirring]
- [呼呼]
- That'll be all for
now, Spongematey.
- 这就是全部了
现在，海绵宝宝。
- Oh, could I just have one
more handshake, Captain?
- 哦，我可以要一份吗
还要握手吗，队长？
- [chuckles]
Sure as yer born.
- [轻笑]
当然，就像你出生的那样。
- Ohh.
- 哦。
- So you two scallywags
want to work for me, eh?
- 所以你们两个无赖
想为我工作，是吗？
both: I wanna be the manager.
两人：我想当经理。
Arrgh.
啊啊。
- Well, you're both in luck.
- 嗯，你们都很幸运。
It just so happens I'm looking
碰巧我正在寻找
for two new manager-erers...
对于两位新任经理...
- Ahh!
- Yeah!
- 啊！
- 是的！
- To manage me toilets.
- 帮我管理厕所。
[chuckling]
[轻笑]
Well, here's another fine mess
you've gotten us into.
好吧，这是另一个混乱的地方
你让我们陷入了困境。
- [whimpering]
- [呜咽]
[coughing]
[咳嗽]
Hair.
头发。
[both grumbling]
[两人都抱怨]
- The humiliation
in here stinks.
- 羞辱
这里很臭。
- This is all your fault,
Plankton.
- 这都是你的错
浮游生物。
I'm gonna keel haul yer
face at lunchtime.
我要龙骨拖你
午餐时的脸。
- Why wait?
- 为什么要等？
Let's take a coffee break.
Pow!
让我们休息一下，喝杯咖啡。
噗！
- Ohh.
- Argh.
- 哦。
- 啊。
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
Swirly.
旋涡状。
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
- Hey, I am trying to read.
- 嘿，我正在努力读书。
Ahh! Hey!
啊！嘿！
Ahh! Ahh!
啊！啊！
- [chuckling]
- Ehh-ehh...ehh.
- [轻笑]
- 呃呃……呃。
- Hmm?
- 唔？
- Two guys...fighting...
toilet paper everywhere
- 两个人……打架……
到处都是卫生纸
- Oh, yeah?
- 哦，是吗？
Who's defiling me
rester-ererooms?
谁玷污我
休息室？
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
- He did it.
- 他做到了。
- No, he did it.
- 不，他做到了。
- Hmm? Hmm? Hmm? Hmm?
- 唔？唔？唔？唔？
- Get off of him, Plankton.
- 离开他，浮游生物。
- It was obviously Krabs'
fault.
- 这显然是蟹老板的
故障。
- Why are you siding
with Plankton?
- 你为什么站在一边
与浮游生物？
- Why are you siding with
Krabs?
- 你为什么站在一边
螃蟹？
- They're arguing.
- 他们在争论。
- And splitting up.
- 然后分手。
- Stop hitting myself.
- Ow.
-别再打自己了。
- 噢。
Stop hitting myself.
别再打自己了。
I'm sick of you.
我厌倦了你。
- What in Neptune's name is
wrong with meself?
- 海王星的名字是什么
我自己有错吗？
Ahh! Oof! Oh!
啊！钱币！哦！
[grumbling]
[抱怨]
- Jeez, is that what
we sound like?
- 天哪，就是这样吗
我们听起来像？
- I hope not, 'cause
that's pathetic.
- 我希望不会，因为
太可悲了。
both: I can't stop hitting
meself,
两人：我无法停止打球
我自己，
because I'm torn.
因为我很伤心。
Arrgh!
啊啊！
[whistles blowing]
[吹口哨]
- All right, you clones,
I want a clean fight,
- 好吧，你们克隆人，
我要一场干净利落的战斗
no rough stuff.
Go back to your corners
没有粗糙的东西。
回到你的角落
when the bell rings
and come out fighting.
当铃声响起时
并出来战斗。
- But first, you gotta
shake hands.
- 但首先你必须
握手。
- Well, fine.
- 好吧，好吧。
both: Ooh, mmm.
两人：哦，嗯。
- Wow, this is a great
handshake.
- 哇，这太棒了
握手。
both: Ehhhh.
两人：嗯嗯。
- Splitting? So soon?
- 分裂？这么快？
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Oh, you.
- 哦，你。
- [coughing]
Hair.
- [咳嗽]
头发。
- Here me, bucko.
- 我在这里，布科。
Let me get that for ya.
让我给你拿一下。
- Bleh!
- 哎呀！
- [chuckling]
- [轻笑]
Freedom.
自由。